ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(远藤达哉原创作品 连载于集英社漫画杂志《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
MISSION:35 PART A: ENJOY THE RESORT TO THE FULLEST
剧名:任务:35 A Part:享受度假胜地吧
Resort island!
度假小岛!
Super landing!
漂亮落地!
Don't jump, you'll trip.
别跳 这样会跌倒
I'm glad the State Security Service is on guard searching for the bomber,
虽然我很感谢安全部人员 持续保持戒备 并搜寻炸弹客踪迹
but I feel their eyes roving about, and it's unnerving.
但他们环顾四周的视线害我好紧张
Father.
父亲
Usually, at times like this, a father would
一般而言在这种时候 普通父亲
jump, skip, and get excited with his daughter. Or so I've heard.
都会跟女儿一起兴奋地蹦蹦跳跳
Let's enjoy the resort island!
我们一起尽情畅玩度假小岛吧!
Father is so simple.
父亲真单纯
- Mother! - Yor!
- 母亲! - 约尔小姐!
- You got our message?
- 你收到我们的信息了?
Yes.
是啊
They gave me a day off today.
上司今天放我一天假
- Is your face a little swollen? - Oh crap. He noticed.
- 你的脸好像有点肿 - 糟糕 被发现了
- Are you okay? - Oh... ah... well...
- 没事吧? - 喔...那个...
Our possible client got in a fight with his wife,
来谈生意的客户跟他太太起了争执
and I got a little hurt when I stepped in to break it up.
我因为插手阻止他们 一个不小心就...
I see. Then what about the attempt to attract them to our city?
这样啊 那招商怎么样了?
That fell through.
那件事...就泡汤了
But we did all we could.
但我们能做的都已经做了
And in the end, they were both smiling.
最后他们脸上也展露笑颜
So I'm satisfied.
所以我很满足
I see.
原来如此
Can you play with us today, Mother?
今天母亲可以跟我们一起玩吗?
Yes, let's have lots of fun!
是啊 一起好好玩吧!
- Let's enjoy! - Let's enjoy ourselves!
- 一起玩! - 一起玩吧!
They look like Bond!
看起来好像邦德!
- It's so nice and peaceful. - It sure is.
- 感觉真是和平 - 是啊
Although the situation on board was pretty threatening.
其实船上的状况很是叫人不安呢
I hope this peace
这样的和平
goes on and on forever.
要是能永远持续下去就好了
In order to make that happen, I will...
为了这个 我...
Father! Mother!
父亲!母亲!
I want to dive in the water and look at the fish!
接下来我想去海里看鱼!
What? That will require us to wear swimsuits, right?
咦?这个活动必须要穿泳装吧?
Oh crap.
惨了
I can't let them see the wound on my chest.
我不能让他们看到我胸前的伤口
Oh never mind. I don't want to get eaten by sharks.
还是算了好了 阿尼亚不想被鲨鱼咬
Oh, but...
咦 不过...
I can probably hide my wound if I wear these swimwear!
穿这种泳装的话就可以遮住了!
Let's try it, Anya!
去看看吧 阿尼亚!
Don't worry. There won't be any sharks.
没事的 不会有鲨鱼的
Even if there is, I'll quietly take them all down.
就算有 我也会暗地里解决掉
THE FISH ARE BEAUTIFUL!
(鱼鱼好漂亮喔!)
YES, THEY LOOK DELICIOUS.
(对啊 看起来好好吃)
- I want to try surfing next! - Let's do it!
- 下一个我想玩冲浪! - 一起去玩吧!
- There's a big wave coming, Anya! - Yes.
- 有大浪要来咯 阿尼亚! - 好
Ready? Go for it!
准备好了吗?出发!
Oh crap! I've been working for days, so I forgot to control my strength!
糟了!工作了几天 一下子忘了控制我的力道!
Anya, are you all right?
阿尼亚 你没事吧?
I want to do it again! Again! It's so thrilling!
再玩一次...刺激感满分!
You better not.
最好不要
I'm so sorry!
对不起!实在对不起!
- We did so many fun things! - We sure did.
- 玩得好开心喔! - 就是说啊
It's almost time to return to the ship.
这时间差不多该回船上去了
You're right.
说得也是
I was fighting without sleep or rest, so I'm suddenly getting sleepy...
一直不眠不休地战斗 突然就觉得好想睡...
Hey... Yor.
等等...约尔小姐?
Father, Anya is sleepy and tired too.
父亲 阿尼亚也想睡了 好累喔
I can understand Anya, but Yor too?
阿尼亚我还能理解 但怎么连约尔小姐都这样?
I guess her job was really exhausting.
看来她的工作真的很辛苦吧
But she still spent all day with Anya to make her happy.
尽管如此 她还是 陪了阿尼亚一整天让她开心
Thanks for your hard work.
真是辛苦你了
SOUVENIR
(手信)
Regarding the incident on Lorelei,
之前罗乐莱公主号上发生的事情
nothing has been made public, but a large number of passengers are missing.
完全没有对外公开 但是有大量乘客失踪
They were all passengers with fake IDs.
那些失踪乘客的身份全都是伪造的
Well, I did notice numerous suspicious individuals on board.
我在船上确实注意到好几个可疑人士
We'll have to be on guard if they're trying to wage war between East and West.
如果他们有意煽动 东西两国之间的战火 就要留心了
The State Security Service believes that a third country is involved.
安全部认为有第三方国家涉入这件事
They'll most likely
不过他们很可能
attempt a cover-up of this incident in order to save face.
会为了保住面子 而把这件事情掩盖过去
As for us,
至于我们这边
we should look out for any extremist groups in Ostania that may
就观察看看东国是否有未知的
yet be unknown.
过激派组织吧
It'll affect Operation Strix as well, so I'm counting on you.
这也会影响到“枭”行动 就拜托你了
Understood.
明白了
And aside from the bomb fiasco,
话说 姑且不管炸弹引发的骚动
how was your vacation?
这次假期过得如何啊?
Was Anya very happy?
阿尼亚小妹妹开心吗?
I've had enough. It was a lot more exhausting than a mission.
真是够了 比出任务还要累人
I can't really tell if he's clever or clumsy.
真搞不清楚 这个男人是精明还是笨拙呢
MISSION:35 PART B: BRAGGING ABOUT VACATION
剧名:任务:35 B Part:炫耀休假
Good morning.
早上好
Yor, you're back already?
前辈 你已经回来啦?
I still can't believe it, Yor.
约尔前辈真是的
It's so unfair that you got to go.
竟然自己去 好狡猾啊
Where's our gift from your cruise trip?
那我们的手信呢?
It was work, remember?
不都说是去工作了吗?
Well, I found some lovely gifts on the ship.
有的 我在船上 找到了一些可爱的礼品
Here it is.
就是这个
SOUVENIR
(手信)
What is this?
这是什么?
It's a skeleton model keychain.
是骷髅造型的钥匙扣
Ugh, this is awful.
这好糟糕喔
I really don't want this.
我一点都不想要
What kind of taste do you have?
这是哪门子的品味?
Usually, souvenirs for coworkers are things like wines or snacks.
一般给同事带手信 都是送红酒还是点心之类的
It's usually something they can consume.
通常都是可以吃的
Oh, is that right?
是...是这样吗?
Father wouldn't buy this for me. Buy it for me, Mother.
这个父亲不会买给我 母亲买给我吧
I said that I'll buy it for you.
我明明有说过要买给你
It's so cool, Anya!
好酷喔 阿尼亚!
I'll buy these as gifts for Camilla and the rest.
就买这个送给卡蜜拉她们当手信吧
Oh no, what should I do?
怎么办好呢?
Loid picked out some snacks as Yuri's gift, but should I give that
劳埃德先生给尤里挑了点心当手信
to these girls?
要改拿那个来送吗?
But there aren't enough for everyone.
可是数量不够分给大家
Oh well, I guess it's very Yor.
不过这就是约尔前辈的风格吧
What? Wine would've definitely been better.
什么?送红酒一定更好啊
Maybe I'll give it to my kid.
我应该会送给我小孩吧
Skip, skip, tra-la-la
我跳 我跳 我跳跳跳
You seem to be in a good mood, Yuri.
尤里 你看起来心情很好呢
Did something good happen with your sister?
你姐姐发生什么好事了吗?
How did you know it was about my older sister?
你怎么知道是我姐姐的事?
Can you read minds?
你会读心吗?
Maybe.
大概吧
My sister returned from her business trip.
我姐姐出公差回来了
I'm going to stop by to see her after work.
下班之后 我要顺路去探望她
It's been so long since I saw her. Sis! Sis!
好久没看到姐姐了 姐姐...
But if Sis is back, that also means he's back...
但如果姐姐回来的话 表示那家伙也回来了...
The preparation is done.
准备就绪
It's a hassle to do all this every time her brother comes over.
每次她弟弟过来都要搞这些真麻烦
Even though he's family, he's the secret police, WISE's enemy.
虽然是家人 但毕竟是 敌方WISE底下的秘密警察
One careless mistake on my part could ruin everything.
任何无心的疏失都可能毁掉一切
Will it be more convincing if I move the pillows closer?
把枕头放近一点 是不是更有说服力?
I'll add some new family pictures
再补放几张新的家庭照吧
and prepare some matching pajamas just in case.
保险起见 还要多准备几套夫妻睡衣
Did you go anywhere during the break?
问你喔 你休假有去哪里玩吗?
I went to the art museum to see some of Pecasso's work.
我去艺术博物馆看了佩加索的作品
I saw an orchestra at the National Opera House.
我去了国家歌剧院听交响乐
You're so lucky.
好好喔
- Good day, Anya. - Good morning.
- 早啊 阿尼亚 - 早上好
You look a little tanned. Did you go somewhere?
你看起来有点晒黑了 是去了哪里吗?
You really want to know, Miss?
小姐 你真的想知道吗?
It's quite a long story, but yes,
说来话长 不过呢
Anya was on the sea that day.
那天阿尼亚到了海上
That was the beginning of a never ending adventure.
那是永不止息的大冒险之始
What character is she playing?
她现在是在演哪出?
I went on board...
阿尼亚搭上了...
- the luxury liner! - What?
- 豪华邮轮! - 什么?
Wow Anya, you're like a celebrity!
阿尼亚 你简直像个名媛淑女呢!
Are you serious?
你不是说真的吧?
You really went on board that legendary ship?
你真的搭上了传说中的那艘船?
It's about time you stop looking down on Anya!
你也该对阿尼亚另眼相看了吧!
I'm sorry, Miss Anya!
真是对不起 阿尼亚!
The Forger family is worthy to visit my house!
福杰一家完全有资格来拜访我家!
Please come!
请务必要来!
Skilled Agent Anya never forgets her mission.
优秀的特工阿尼亚从没忘过她的任务
I see. So it was just an ordinary break.
什么啊 很普通嘛
It wasn't ordinary at all! It was super big.
一点都不普通好不好! 那艘船真的超级大
It was some ship called Princess Lalalalai.
名字叫做什么“乐乐来”公主号
Princess Lorelei?
罗乐莱公主号?
I went on that before school started.
开学前我就搭过了
It was so-so, wasn't it?
感觉一般般而已啊
I stayed at the Imperial Suite,
我那时候住在皇家套房
but their furnishings were nothing to rave about.
不过他们的装潢品味实在不值得一提
Anya stayed in the third-class prison.
阿尼亚住的是三等舱牢房
If I had stayed in the third-class cabin I'd be too embarrassed to talk about it.
我要是住在三等舱的话 肯定丢脸到说不出口
Stop it. Have pity on the commoner.
好了 稍微可怜一下庶民吧
I flew over the skies of Münk on a helicopter the day before yesterday.
前天我可是搭了直升机 在慕克上空翱翔呢
It was so much fun.
超级好玩的
We stayed at the first-class hotel in Bayan
我们住了拜恩的高级饭店
and ate lots of good food!
还吃了超多好吃的东西!
So what?
那又怎样?
I asked Papa for a favor,
我拜托了我爸爸
and partied with Rachel, the actress from Berlint in Love.
跟《巴林特之爱》的 女演员瑞秋一起开派对
There were about 100 guests and I heard stories behind the drama and got gifts.
那天宾客就有上百名 除了听到幕后花絮 我还收到礼物
I had so much fun.
有够好玩的
That's so amazing, Becky!
好厉害喔 贝姬!
It's the Blackbell Heavy Industries after all.
真不愧是布莱克贝尔重工业
You're on a whole different level.
格局不是常人可比的
- Hehe. - Tell us all about Rachel!
跟我们说点瑞秋的事情啊!
Is she really pretty in person?
她本人真的很漂亮吗?
Introduce her to me!
也介绍给我认识嘛!
Anya's ship had about 100 dangerous people on board.
阿尼亚的船上也有上百个厉害人物
What do you mean by "dangerous people"?
什么厉害人物?
Were there celebrities on board?
难不成船上有什么艺人吗?
Who was it?
是谁啊?
There were some from foreign countries.
有些人是从国外来的
- What? - Foreign celebrities? That's amazing.
- 什么? - 外国艺人?好厉害喔
Don't keep us in suspense. Give us some names!
不要吊我们胃口嘛! 说几个名字来听听
For example,
举例来说嘛
Sickle-and-Chain Barnaby!
锁链手巴纳比!
Who is that?
那是谁啊?
Who is that? Never heard of him.
谁啊?从来没听过
- Is it a street performer? - Who else was there?
- 是街头艺人吗? - 其他还有谁?
Oh... um...
喔 那个...
The elephant tamer Paon-man.
驯象师炮欧曼...
And Shashasha-man who can teleport.
还有可以瞬间移动的虾虾虾曼...
What kind of people are they? Are they in a circus?
这都是些什么人啊? 是马戏团的人吗?
They're... villains.
他们是...坏蛋
- Villains? - Did you run into pirates or something?
- 坏蛋? - 难道是遇上海贼了还什么吗?
How unfortunate for you.
也太倒霉了吧
I didn't see any stories like that on the news.
新闻都没有报导这件事啊
Don't take it seriously.
不用跟她认真啦
That's right! They covered-up that incident caused by the bad guys.
对了 政府把坏人 造成的意外掩盖起来了
I wasted my time listening to you.
听你讲这些真是浪费我时间
Tsk, tsk. It's not on the news,
啧啧 新闻没有报出来
because they are secret villains that the government
就是因为呢 这些坏蛋的存在是连政府
doesn't even know about.
都不知道的秘密
They came up from the bottom of the sea. Their true identity is...
他们是从海底来的 真面目是...
Octopeople.
章鱼星人
Heroic Anya secretly took them down
勇者阿尼亚暗地里用刺人的东西
with the stabbing tool...
把他们打倒了...
Mother did.
其实是母亲打倒的
And what did you talk about with Rachel?
所以你跟瑞秋都聊了什么?
Introduce her to me!
介绍给我嘛!
- And world's peace... - No way!
- 所以世界和平... - 骗人!
Samantha was there too?
萨曼莎也去了?
- You're so lucky. - I want to see her too!
- 好好喔 - 我也想看到本人!
She has no shame.
那家伙还真行
She's such a big liar.
撒谎也不打草稿
It's remarkable, in a way.
就某种意义上而言也很了不起
I never get tired of watching her.
看她出包都看不腻
What's with the elephant taming Octopeople?
驯象的章鱼星人又是什么鬼?
You're absolutely right.
就是啊
Take your seats everyone.
好了 回座位坐好
Did everyone enjoy their break?
大家休假有好好享受吗?
Teacher, Forger says that she took down some Octopeople.
老师 福杰说她打败了章鱼星人
Oh, that's impressive.
哦 那真是了不起呢
I understand, Anya.
我明白喔 阿尼亚
Humans have the tendency and urge to fib in order to impress others.
人类有时会 急于让他人印象深刻而说谎
But if you do that,
但是人都是这样的
and try to become the ideal version of yourself,
再一边努力成为理想中的自己
you can become a lovely lady.
就能变成一位优秀的淑女喔
- That's what Mama told me. - Becky!
- 我妈妈是这样告诉我的 - 贝姬...
But don't lie too much, because if you do, you'll end up all alone like me.
不过 撒谎还是不要撒过头的好 小心变成跟我一样的边缘人喔
Sis! It's been so long! I haven't seen you in so long, Sis!
姐姐 好久不见! 好久没看到我姐姐啦!
Here's your souvenir.
来 送你的手信
Yay! I'll treasure it forever.
我会好好珍藏的
Eat it before it expires.
记得在过期之前吃完喔
Then I'll take a picture of it, and gaze at it every day.
那我就拍张照起来每天看
He's so loud.
有够吵
- Anya's home. - Welcome home.
- 阿尼亚回来了 - 欢迎回家
What's wrong, Anya?
怎么了 阿尼亚?
You exaggerated and stretched the truth, and your classmates made fun of you?
把事情讲得言过其实 结果被同学嘲笑了?
They called me a liar.
他们说我是骗子
Anya cried a little.
阿尼亚哭了一下下
Why did you lie?
为什么要撒这种谎?
- For Plan B! - How do you know about that?
- 为了计划B啊! - 你从哪知道的?
I wanted to stand out.
因为想让大家注意我嘛
If you let emotions take over, and lie instinctively, you'll destroy yourself.
如果这样任凭感情用事 而随口说谎的话 会害死自己喔
If you want to disguise yourself, do it strategically and thoroughly.
如果想要伪装自己 就要有策略 做得更全面
Stake your life.
赌上自己的性命
To make your lies convincing, add in some details,
谎言要具有说服力 就必须加入细节
and sprinkle some truth in it.
然后多少夹杂一点真实性
But be bold...
不过要大胆点...
Oh I see...
哦 是吗?这样啊
But lying is bad.
但撒谎是不好的行为喔
I've seen many liars.
我看过太多骗子了
Humans who lie are all scumbags.
会撒谎的人都是人渣
They're scum who are nothing but pests ruining this country.
那些人渣是群只会毁灭国家的害虫
Me? I'm lying about my current status for the sake of Sis.
我?我是为了姐姐好 才隐瞒我目前的身分
Everything I do for Sis is in the name of justice.
我为姐姐做的一切都是出于正义
Yes, liars are all scumbags.
没错 骗子都是人渣
Yes... That's right...
说...说得对呢
It's best to show your true self, as much as possible.
最好还是尽量展现真诚的自己
That'll help you to get along with everyone too.
这样跟其他人才能好好相处喔
Being a liar seems complicated, so I won't lie anymore.
撒谎实在糟透了 所以阿尼亚不会再撒谎了
MISSION:36 PART A: BERLINT IN LOVE
(任务:36 A Part:巴林特恋曲)
PART B: NIGHTFALL'S DAILY LIFE
(B Part:〈夜帷〉的日常)
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译:洪贞韵